kaiusaltd.com 2019-03-08

# Privacy Policy | KAI USA ltd.

This Online Privacy Policy specifies the information Kai USA Ltd. (Kershaw Knives, Shun Cutlery, Zero Tolerance Knives, and Kai Housewares) collects and how we use that information. The amount and type of information that we receive depends on how you use the site.

This Policy applies to our online practices only. It was last updated on June 26, 2018. We reserve the right to change any part of the Kai USA Online Privacy Policy at any time. If you have questions or comments regarding this policy, please use the Contact Us form to get in touch with us.

##  ABOUT THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT & HOW WE USE IT

###  WHEN YOU VISIT OUR WEBSITE

As a visitor to our website, you can always browse without providing personal information. The information does not personally identify you and cannot be linked back to you unless you decide at some point to identify yourself.

Website Analytics

We use Google Analytics to gather statistics and measure our website activity so that we can better understand our customer base. If you are browsing, we may collect the following information, which is not personally identifying information:

  * Browser type and operating system
  * Date and time you accessed our site
  * Number of times you accessed our site
  * Whether your computer is enabled for Javascript or cookies
  * Language preference from your browser
  * Applications and plug-ins
  * Pages you visit
  * If you came to our site from another website, the address of that site

We have also implemented IP Anonymization in Google Analytics to further protect your privacy. All IP addresses are “masked” as they are received by the Analytics Collection Network and before they are processed or stored. This prevents data from going to Google Analytics with an identifiable IP address and protects your privacy.

Use of Cookies

  * Cookies are pieces of information that are sent by our website and stored on your computer’s hard drive or temporarily in the computer’s memory.
  * We may use session cookies, which terminate when you close your browser, and/or persistent cookies, which remain on your computer until manually deleted.
  * Cookies can help you move faster through our site, remember your preferences, and help us estimate our audience and what web pages they visit.
  * The use of cookies, or similar technologies, is an industry standard and you will find them on most major websites.
  * For more information about cookies, visit http://www.allaboutcookies.org
  * See below for information on how to control cookie use.

Advertising

_Kai USA currently does not use:_

  * Remarketing with Google Analytics
  * Google Display Network Impression Reporting

_We do use:_

  * Google Analytics Demographics & Interest Reporting
  * Google Analytics tracking codes

Should this change in the future, we will update this Online Privacy Policy.

We do not/will not facilitate the merging of personally identifiable information with non-personally identifiable information previously collected from Display Advertising features that are based on the DoubleClick cookie unless you have specifically opted-in to that merger. We will not attempt to disaggregate data that Google reports in aggregate.

####  How We Use this Information

Cookies and similar technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies on an individual as well as an aggregated basis. By showing how and when visitors use the site, cookies help Kai USA better determine which areas of our site are popular and which areas are not.

We use Google tracking codes for advertising campaign reporting when we place advertising on other websites or email lists. These reports are aggregate and non-personally identifiable. This reporting is shared internally with Kai USA and Kai Corp personnel only.

##  OPT-IN/OPT-OUT

###  Cookies

Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies. If you'd prefer, you can set your browser to refuse cookies or to alert you when cookies are being sent. However, it is possible that some parts of our site will not function properly without being able to use cookies.

###  Analytics

If you prefer that your information not be included in Google Analytics’ aggregated information on our website, [you can get a browser opt-out add-on from Google here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/). 

###  Personalized Ads

There are a number of ways you can opt-out of personalized online advertising. Please note that opting out of targeted ads will not prevent you from seeing online ads. It will, however, prevent the ads from being customized to you based on your browsing behavior.

Here are links to websites where you can opt-out of personalized advertising:

  * Google Ad Choices—Sign in to your Google Account, navigate to Personal info & privacy, click Ad Settings, then Manage Ad Settings
  * [TrustArc](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) (US & EU)
  * In the EU—[Your Online Choices](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)

###  Anonymous Browsing

You can also use the Incognito browsing window in Google’s Chrome browser so that it won't save your browsing history, cookies and site data, or information entered in forms. [Get more information here.](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95464?co=GENIE.Platform%3DDesktop&hl=en) Other browsers have similar options; search “anonymous browsing” and the name of your browser to learn more.

##  WHEN YOU MAKE PURCHASES ON THIS WEBSITE

Purchases made through this site are completed using the Kibo system. During the course of making a purchase transaction, personally identifiable information will be collected, including your credit card information, to process your transactions, maintain your accounts, and offer additional products and services to you. Kibo will not collect this information without informing you first. It is your option to provide the information. The Kibo Privacy Statement applies to purchases made through this website and you must agree to the terms of this Privacy Statement and the use of your personal data in order to make purchases through this site.

##  OTHER INTERACTIONS VIA THIS WEBSITE

###  Reviews/Comments/Testimonials

What We Collect

When you provide a review or comment on our website, we ask you to provide a username, email address, and your location. Only your review or comment appears publicly on the website, along with your username and state/province.

Why We Collect It

We monitor reviews and comments as feedback on our products and services. We ask for your email in case we need to communicate with you about your review or comment privately. This information is only shared internally.

Your Options

This information is stored on our secure website servers. If you prefer not to have your comments published but still wish to communicate with us, please use the Contact Us form. If you wish to have a published review, comment, or testimonial removed, please contact us at info@kai-usa.com.

###  Contact Us/Customer Service/Warranty Service/Shun Knife Registration

What We Collect

We collect personally identifiable information on our Contact Us, Warranty & Sharpening Request, and our Shun Knife Registration forms.

Why We Collect It

We use this information to be able to respond to your requests and questions in a personal and timely manner, or to be able to process your warranty request and return your serviced product or products to you.

Your Options

This information is stored on our secure website servers and is only shared internally. If you wish to have this information corrected or deleted, please contact us. If you prefer, you may contact us by phone, toll free, at 800-325-2891 or locally at 503-682-1966. You may email us directly at info@kai-usa.com. If you wish to have any of these interactions deleted, please contact us at info@kai-usa.com.

###  Sweepstakes, Giveaways, Or Other Promotions

What We Collect

When you enter a sweepstakes, giveaway, or other promotional event via our website or social media, we may ask for personally identifiable information in order to process your entry. In those cases, your information may also be shared with other carefully selected companies, such as our sweepstakes application provider. These companies are required to maintain the confidentiality of the information and are restricted from using the information for any unauthorized purpose. Depending on the method of participation in the promotion, you may also interact with social media platforms such as Facebook and Instagram.

Why We Collect It

This information is collected solely in order to process your entry. Other than the sweepstakes application processor, we do not share this information and we do not use it to market to you, unless such use is disclosed to you at the time of entry.

Your Options

By entering a sweepstakes, giveaway, or other promotional event, you agree to provide us with your information and to allow us to share that information, as needed, with associated companies. If you do not agree, please do not enter our sweepstakes, giveaways, or promotional events.

Here are links to the privacy policies of such associated companies:

###  Email Communications

What We Collect

When you sign up to our email newsletter for updates on new products, sales, promotions, and other email communications and content, we ask for your name, email address, zip/postal code, and country, as well as your preferences for what information you will receive by email. You will specifically be asked to opt-in to our email list.

Why We Collect It

We collect this information so that we can email you directly, personalize your email, and make sure that you receive the types of communications you prefer from us.

Your Options

You can subscribe to our email communications on the product pages of our website and from a link in the footer on any page of the website. You can unsubscribe anytime from the Unsubscribe link in the bottom of any email you receive from us.

We use MailChimp as our marketing automation platform. The information you provide will be transferred to MailChimp for processing in accordance with their [Privacy Policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/)  and [Terms](https://mailchimp.com/legal/).

We occasionally use Survey Monkey as our survey platform. The information you provide will be transferred to Survey Monkey for processing in accordance with their [Privacy Policy](https://www.surveymonkey.com/mp/legal/privacy-policy/) and [Terms](https://www.surveymonkey.com/mp/legal/terms-of-use/).

###  Job Applications

What We Collect

As part of the job application process, we collect personally identifying information and, in many cases, applicants will also attach a resume.

Why We Collect It

We collect this information to be able to review it, then get in touch with appropriate candidates for a wide range of positions at Kai USA.

Your Options

This information is stored on our secure website servers and is only shared internally. If you prefer not to apply on our website, you can search out our positions on a wide variety of the most commonly used employment-search websites. You may also call the front desk locally at 503-682-1966.

###  ADDITIONAL DISCLOSURE TO THIRD PARTIES

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. We may share this information with trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or serving you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. Our website partners have access to the information on our website, though they do not generally access it unless trying to solve an issue with the operation of the website.

We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety.

##  SECURITY

For site security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, this site may monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage. If security monitoring reveals evidence of possible abuse or criminal activity, system personnel may provide the results of such monitoring to appropriate officials. Except for authorized law enforcement investigations, no attempts are made to identify individual users or their usage habits. Unauthorized attempts to upload information or change information on this site are strictly prohibited and may be punishable under the State law and Federal statutes including the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986, the National Information Infrastructure Protection Act of 1996, the Electronic Communications Privacy Act of 1986, and the Cybersecurity Enhancement Act of 2012.

###  TRANSMISSION OF INFORMATION

Kai USA and its website partners make every effort to ensure the secure collection and transmission of sensitive user information using industry-accepted data collection and encryption methodologies.

SSL (Secure Sockets Layer)

This website is secured by a RapidSSL RCA SSL certificate with a SHA256 with RSA signature, using TLS 1.2 protocol. Cipher suites have been optimized to follow best practices and return an A+ rating by ssllabs.com.

Database (Amazon Web Services Reliable Database Storage)

This website uses Amazon Web Services (AWS) for secure reliable database storage and transport within a secure Amazon Virtual Private Cloud. Backed by the security and best practices offered by AWS, we use industry standards and best practices to prevent unauthorized access to stored data. The Amazon Virtual Private Cloud allows us to control, monitor and secure traffic and access to this website and data in an isolated manner. AWS resources are kept up-to-date with the latest security protocols and patches to prevent threats from vulnerabilities.

E-commerce

Credit card information is not stored on the Kai USA website or database, and is only processed through a secure third-party payment provider over an SSL encryption.

###  CHILDREN’S ONLINE PRIVACY

The Kai USA website is not directed at children under the age of thirteen and we do not knowingly collect information from children under the age of thirteen. If we become aware that we have inadvertently received information from a visitor under the age of thirteen through this website, we will delete the information from our records.

##  TERMS OF USE

###  LIMITATION ON SCOPE OF CONTENT

The Kai USA website contains information regarding Kai USA, its brands and products—Kershaw Knives, Shun Cutlery, Zero Tolerance Knives, and Kai Housewares products—and its promotional programs. At this time, the products sold through this website are offered for sale only in the United States and Canada. The promotional programs, if any, described in this site are available only in the United States and Canada. Pricing information referred to on this site is in U.S. dollars and Canadian dollars.

###  NO REPRESENTATION OR WARRANTY

Kai USA reserves the right to modify the information contained in this site at any time without notice. We reserve the right to change specifications and/or features of products without notice at any time. While we make all reasonable efforts to ensure that material on this site is correct, accuracy cannot be guaranteed and Kai USA does not assume any responsibility for the accuracy, completeness or authenticity of any information contained in this site. This site, and all information and materials contained herein, are provided to you "as is" and without warranty of any kind. Dealer contact information is provided for the sole purpose of aiding customers in locating a dealer. Kai USA is not responsible for any transactions or commerce with any third parties.

This site may contain links to other websites that are completely independent of this site. Neither Kai USA nor any agency, officer, or employee of Kai USA, or of its affiliates or parent company, makes any representation or warranty as to the accuracy, completeness or authenticity of the information contained in any such link, and any link to the website of another person or entity shall not in any manner be construed as endorsement by Kai USA of such person's or entity's website, products or services. Visiting or linking to any other off-site pages or other sites is at your own risk. Your confidential use of this site cannot be guaranteed by Kai USA. Kai USA shall not be responsible for any harm that you or any person may suffer as a result of a breach of confidentiality with respect to your use of this site or any information you transmit to this site.

###  COPYRIGHT/TRADEMARK OWNERSHIP

This site is copyright Kai USA Ltd., 2014. You may use the information, text or graphics contained in this site only for your personal use and may not reproduce, adapt or publish it, in whole or in part, for any purpose without the express written consent of Kai USA. Kai USA dealers may freely use the information, photos, and graphics in the Media Gallery for each brand. Access may be received from your Kai USA Customer Service Representative. Kershaw Knives, Shun Cutlery, and Zero Tolerance marks and designs are registered trademarks of the Kai Group. Kai USA is a member of the Kai Group, Japan.

###  Kai USA Retailers Credit Card Payment Terms and Conditions

###  Authorization 

By entering your credit card information you (i) state that you are an authorized user of the credit card and that the associated information entered (e.g., account holder name, account number, billing address) is accurate, (ii) you authorize Kai USA Ltd to charge the amount you have requested to your credit card, and (iii) authorize Kai USA Ltd to return to your credit card any funds due to you by Kai USA Ltd resulting from use of this Service.

###  Charges

For each transaction, in addition to the charge you have authorized, your credit card issuer and network may assess their customary transaction or handling charge, if any. If a charge is declined or reversed by the credit card issuer or network, you agree to pay us a service charge and to reimburse us for all reasonable costs of collection. Your credit card issuer may also assess its customary charge for such transactions.

###  Confirmation of Payment

By clicking “Submit,” you are consenting to receive a one-time confirmation of this payment electronically to the email address you have provided to us. Sensitive information should NEVER be provided via e-mail. Remember, legitimate businesses and organizations with which you maintain a relationship already have all the information they need about you. If you receive an e-mail purporting to be from Kai USA Ltd. and you are unsure if it is legitimate, please call us using a telephone number that you know is ours (e.g., on your invoice or statement) prior to responding to it.
